

Ammar Ibrahim Rashid

Network Engineer

Baghdad ,iraq / <u>ammar.i.rashid@gmail.com</u> https://www.linkedin.com/in/ammar-ibrahim-749a38135

> Mobile:07703978770 CISCO ID : CSCO12684914

Personal Summary

Network Engineer with more than 15 years of experience in Network & Internet fields. I have experience in Cisco and Mikrotik Devices. An enthusiastic network engineer with the necessary drive and determination needed to resolve complex networking issues. Possessing effective organisational skills and excellentworking knowledge of networking technologies and having a commitment to keep up to date with the latest developments. Experienced in providing motivation, guidance and a up to date networking consultancy service to both colleagues and clients.

Education

Academic Education

University Of Technology - Electrical Engineering (2004)

Mikrotik

- ➤ MikroTik Certified Network Associate MTCNA (1512NA477)
- ➤ MikroTik Certified Routing Engineer MTCRE (1602RE063)
- MikroTik Certified Wireless Engineer MTCWE (1501WE077)
- MikroTik Certified Traffic Control Engineer MTCTCE (1302TCE050)
- MikroTik Certified User Management Engineer MTCUME (1512UME001)
- MikroTik Certified Inter-networking Engineer MTCINE (1602INE007)

Microsoft

- Microsoft certified Server Exchange 2010 (Course)
- Microsoft Certified IT Professional (MCITP) (Course)

Cisco System

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Cisco Certified Network Professional (CCNP)
 - CCNP Implementing Cisco IP Routing 300-101
 - CCNP Implementing Cisco IP Switched Networks 300-115
 - CCNP Troubleshooting and Maintaining Cisco IP Networks 300-135
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Security (CCNA Security 210-260 IINS)

Fortinet

Fortinet NSE 4 Network Security Professional

Management Courses

Project Management Professional (PMP) (Course)

Skills

- Administering & designing LANs, WANs internet/intranet.
- ➤ Installation and configuration of V-sat equipment.
- ➤ Implementing and Troubleshooting Wireless Network.
- ➤ Worked on PRTG for bandwidth related cases.
- Worked on Dude Server.
- Cisco & Mikrotik devices configuration in particular configuration/troubleshooting.
- ➤ Worked on L2 and L3 MPLS and internet related bandwidth issue.
- ➤ Implementing and Troubleshooting MPLS VPN Networked.
- Configured and troubleshooting EBGP and IBGP.
- ➤ Implementing security policies using ACL, Firewall, IPSEC, SSL, VPN, IPS/IDS, AAA (TACACS+ & RADIUS).
- ➤ Dealt with monitoring tools like network packet capture tools like Wire-shark.
- ➤ Installation, Configuration and Administration of Windows Servers 2008/2012.
- ➤ Troubleshooting of complex LAN/WAN infrastructure, including routing protocols EIGRP, OSPF & BGP.
- ➤ High availability cluster.

Work Experience

- ➤ Worked on Computer Maintenance in Al-Sina'a Street (2004-2005).
- ➤ Worked in Internet Center and Vsat installation and Maintenance (2005-2011).
 - Vsat installation (Installation Maintenance-Support)
 - Installation Mikrotik Server and featuers.
 - Design and implementation of wired and wireless networks (PtP&PtMP).
- ➤ Worked in Al Hadetha Co. for Software & Automation as a Network Engineer then Administrator for Network Department (2011-2017).
- ➤ Worked in New Vision Co. for IT Solutions as Manager of Network Department. (2017-2018)
- ➤ Worked in Techno Fast Co. as Network Administrator (2018- Up to now).
- Cisco Courses Instructor in New Horizons Training Center in Baghdad.
- Cisco Courses Instructor in Ebdaa Training Center in Baghdad.

Projects

- > Design and implementation of Core network to internet service provider for Al Hadetha Co.
 - BGP
 - Internet Service Management
 - Wireless Network
 - Management and monitoring:
 - PRTG
 - Dude
 - Billing System Management (SAS RADIUS).
 - Design and implementation of RF planning for Al Hadetha Co. (Repeater Towers)
 - Power
- Implementation of wired network to Huawei building in Baghdad.
- Implementation of E-government network of The State Co. for Marketing Drugs & Medical Appliances (Kimadia):
 - Server Room
 - Core network
 - Wired network
 - Wireless network with Branch offices and stores.
 - Security
 - High availability cluster
- ➤ Design and implementation of wireless network for wireless IP camera system project for Almco group of companies in Basra.
- Design and implementation of Data Center for Union Bank of Iraq.
- Design and implementation of LAN system for the Al-Manafaa Bank building including all hardware.
- ➤ Design and implementation Server Room for Al-Manafaa Bank.
- ➤ Design and implementation of Network, Servers and Security for Laserfiche Software (Enterprise Content Management Software) for Iraqi Anti-Corruption Academy.
- ➤ Design and implementation of Techno Fast Automation Co. Network:
 - Main Data Center & Core network
 - BGP
 - Internet Service Management
 - NOC
 - Wireless Towers & Network
 - Voice Service & GSM Gateway
 - Management and monitoring:
 - PRTG
 - Dude
 - InfiMONITOR (Wireless Network Monitoring)
 - Syslog
 - Access Control System
 - Power

- > Design and implementation of wireless network for wireless IP camera system project for Basra Oil Company (BOC) (South Oil Company Complex-HQ).
- > Design and implementation of National Petroleum Services (NPS) in Basra.
 - Data Center
 - LAN & Wireless Network.
 - Fiber Optic Network
 - Internet Service Management
 - Voice Network
 - IP Camera Network
 - WAN & VPN
 - Vsat
- Design and implementation Network of Panalpina Global Transport and Logistics in Basra.
 - LAN Network
 - Wireless Network
 - Internet Service Management
 - Vsat
- ➤ Design and implementation Network of National Energy Oilfield Services:
 - LAN & Wireless Network.
 - Voice Network & Service
 - Internet Service Management.



